Ho Boon Wee Addison

Mobile: +65 97308124 Email: addisonho@u.nus.edu

Skype: addisonho@outlook.com
Online Resume: addisonho.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/addison-ho-8a2378176/

GitHub: github.com/carrein



Personal Statement

Internship Objectives

I am interested in building software products which leverage the dynamics of a social community to benefit the end user. My objectives are to build on the relevant skill sets necessary to develop such products. I picked Silicon Valley particularly due to its well-established technological and start-up scene. Here, I yearn to experience the vibrant culture of the country, build quality relationships with my mentors and peers and learn from their entrepreneurial spirit.

About Me

I am a Year 2 Computer Science student enrolled at the National University of Singapore. I enjoy teaching and was a Teaching Assistant for two programming modules (CS1010, CS2030) during my second year. I enjoy tinkering and am currently embarking on a start-up with a small team to build a social networking application. I also greatly enjoy working in teams where I am given the opportunity to learn the different thinking processes of my colleagues.

Strengths and Weaknesses

I am flexible and can work in various capacities. Apart from technological abilities, I have worked as a logistician during my stint in National Service, a mandatory two years military service, and here I performed a spectrum of tasks such as liaising with large companies, picking up goods, hosting cohesion activities. I am willing to hunker down and learn what is required of me regardless of the job scope. I will take charge and ask questions when the subject matter is unclear or there are no clear directions given.

However, I admit that there are times where I come across as stubborn as I am usually firm about my decisions. This has led to occasional disagreement during projects, but I always make it a point to settle the issue amicably and ensure all parties are placated. I am excited to see how I can better enhance my soft skills especially in a foreign environment and remain logical and deliver quality work even under intense pressure.

Experiences

From Dec 2019 to Jan 2019, I was employed as a Data Management Intern in a short stint with United Overseas Bank Singapore. Here, I was engaged in the company's data lake project and aided in data mapping and raising issues using their in-house tools. I am currently vying for a summer internship from May 2019 to July 2019 to further prepare my technical capabilities before flying off for internship overseas with NUS Overseas College.

Skillsets

I am adept with popular languages (Java, Dart, C) and have employed other languages (Python, JavaScript, Ruby, C#) for smaller scale projects. Additionally, I am well versed with the web stack and its frameworks and have set up both front-end (HTML, CSS, jQuery) and back-end (Rails, Sinatra, Nginx, Apache, Google Cloud Platform) systems for a variety of applications. I was previously certified as a Red Hat Certified System Administrator 6 and know how to operate various deployment platforms as well (Digital Ocean, Heroku). I am experienced in the tools commonly associated with software engineering workflows such as Git and unit testing. I am a huge proponent of good UI/UX design and am confident in design tools (Photoshop/Illustrator) and web CSS frameworks (Bulma, Bootstrap).

How I Can Contribute

I am interested in exploring and learning different roles and would love to contribute to the company in various aspects. As I am currently working on my start-up, I am also extremely interested in understanding the undertaking required to run a successful start-up such seeding, market research and learning the environment required to set-up a successful company. Hence, I am confident that I am a good candidate for most projects and hope to contribute greatly to the success of any company.

HO BOON WEE ADDISON 1

Education

Aug 2017 - Present Singapore National University of Singapore Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science. Current GPA: 3.91/5.00. Apr 2013 - Apr 2015 Singapore Singapore Polytechnic Diploma with Merit in Computer Engineering. Specialized in Embedded Systems and Networking. CGPA: 3.83/4.00. Work Experience Dec 2018 - Jan 2019 Singapore United Overseas Bank Data Management Intern Five weeks internship at United Overseas Bank Singapore. Worked on EDAG and accompanying FRR Data Lake Project. Assisted the User Acceptance Team in performing database mapping troubleshooting. Dec 2017 – Dec 2018 National University of Singapore Singapore Teaching Assistant Modules conducted: Programming Methodology I / II. Responsible for conducting lab lessons and material preparation. Roles include assignment grading and student feedback. May 2015 - May 2017 Singapore Republic of Singapore Navy Supply Assistant Served two years of National Service. Responsible for unit's stores, transportation requests and issuing Purchase Orders and Approval of Requests. Jul 2014 – Sep 2014 Singapore Deutsche Telekom Asia Pte. Ltd Industrial Attachment Two months internship at a German MNC. Responsible for handling customer records for billing claims. Employed Microsoft Excel and Visual Basic to sort customer data. Scholastic Achievement/Extracurricular Activities Apr 2019 Singapore typet – Flutter Create Challenge Contest organized my Google to develop a mobile application using the Flutter framework in 5kb or less. Application pulls lyrics through a free web API and allows user to find out their average typing word per minute (WPM). Jan 2019 Singapore payleh! – Hack n Roll 2019 Hackathon to develop a Telegram bot that tracks group expenses. Developed with Java and Google's Firebase. Responsible for front end UI and integration with Cloud Firestore. Oct 2019 Singapore taskMe - Code-for-Asia 2018 A two days hackathon to develop a social enterprise platform. Platform for users to post and complete menial tasks. Responsible for application UI/UX.

HO BOON WEE ADDISON 2

May 2018 – Aug 2018	 safetriphome – Orbital project A two-person project to develop a geolocation based social networking application. Responsible for frontend and backend development. Application was built with Flutter and project's backend uses Sinatra paired with MariaDB for database retrieval. Awarded Gemini level of project achievement. 	Singapore
Sep 2018	 RUNNUS 2018 Designed and deployed RUNNUS webpage using Bulma CSS framework. Committee member under Route Management team, responsible for delineating race routes and logistics. 	Singapore
June 2018	 Freshman Orientation Project Committee member for School of Computing Freshman Social Camp, Orientation Camp and Receiving and Giving (RAG) event. Conducted camp schedules and provided logistical and transportation support for over 1000 freshmen across three camps. 	Singapore
Apr 2014 – Apr 2015	 Guardian Angel A six-man, year long project to create a smart mobile wheelchair. Developed with Arduino and Electroencephalogram technology. Awarded Social Engagement and Entrepreneurship Gold prize. 	Singapore

Skillsets and Proficiency

Spoken

Written

Programming	Java Dart C Ruby JavaScript	Proficient Proficient Intermediate Basic Basic		
Web	HTML, CSS, JQuery	Intermediate		
Database	Firebase (Google Cloud Platform) MYSQL	Proficient Basic		
Application Development	Flutter Sinatra Ruby on Rails Unity JavaFX	Proficient Intermediate Intermediate Basic Basic		
Server Management	Red Hat Certified Server Administrator 6 (Expired)			
Multimedia	Adobe Photoshop Sony Vegas Adobe Illustrator	Proficient Intermediate Basic		
Operating Systems	Linux Windows 10, 8.1, 7	Proficient Proficient		
Office Productivity	Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel	Proficient		
Typesetting	LaTeX	Intermediate		
Language Proficiency				

HO BOON WEE ADDISON 3

English – Fluent; Mandarin – Fluent; Korean - Basic

English - Competent; Chinese - Basic; Korean - Basic

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 3.91 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2017	Year 1/Semester 1	Roots and Wings - Personal and Interpersonal Effectiveness 1.0	CS
		Programming Methodology II	В
		Computer Organization	B+
		Public Speaking and Critical Reasoning	B+
		Introductory Mathematics	B+
		Fundamentals of Physics II	B+
Jan – May 2018	Year 1/Semester 2	Discrete Structures	A
		Data Structures and Algorithms	В
		Introduction to Computer Networks	B+
		Superhero Entertainments	S
		Quantitative Reasoning	S
		Calculus for Computing	B+
Aug – Nov 2018	Year 2/Semester 1	Independent Software Development Project (ORBITAL)	CS
		Introduction to Operating Systems	В
		Design and Analysis of Algorithms	В
		Asking Questions	CS
		Changing Landscapes of Singapore	S
		Linear Algebra I	S
Jan – May 2019	Year 2/Semester 2	Communicating in the Information Age	In-progress
		Probability and Statistics	In-progress
		Software Engineering #	In-progress
		Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	In-progress
		Korean I	In-progress

[#]The Software Engineering Project focuses on developing an individual's capabilities by working in teams to write a software application compromising of >10K LoC. The original code provided was address book application written in Java. Our team morphed the application to a minimal photo editor including features such as cropping, filters and layers. The entire project adheres to core software engineering principles such as unit testing, continuous integration and version control.

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn



United Overseas Bank Limited

HEAD OFFICE 80 Raffles Place UOB Plaza Singapore 048624 Tel (65) 6533 9898 Fax (65) 6534 2334 uobgroup com

Co. Reg. No. 193500026Z

To Whom It May Concern

INTERNSHIP TESTIMONIAL

Mr Ho Boon Wee Addison completed his UOB internship as a Data Management Intern from 10 December 2018 to 11 January 2019 under my supervision and the guidance of the User Acceptance Team for the following assignments:

Nature of Assignments:

- Learning about the Enterprise Data Architecture Group and the accompanying FRR Data Lake project.
- Assisting in Teradata database entries mapping alongside the data management team.

Tasks accomplished:

- Demonstrated high ability in understanding business logic and workflow process in an enterprise data governance and management project.
- Actively engaged with UAT and Teradata testers in performing troubleshooting for database entries.
- Consolidated daily deliverables summaries such as IRA issues due dates.
- Performed mapping clean up on database entries for query testing.

During this internship, Addison displayed good work ethics and programming ability. He also demonstrated great understanding and analytical skill when approaching a variety of assigned duties. I am impressed with Addison's aptitude for learning. Despite the scope of the team's project falling out of the purview of the major which he is enrolled in, Addison communicated well with the members of the team to try and grasp a clearer understanding of the project's requirements and its deliverables.

He takes pride in his work and exhibits great attention to detail, finishing his work punctually, additionally, sitting in during meetings if there is a further need for clarifications.

Addison will be an asset to any employers and we highly recommend him for any ventures he chooses to pursue in the future.

Sincerely,

UNITED OVERSEAS BANK SINGAPORE, DATA MANAGEMENT OFFICE

HELEN CHAU

Senior Vice President at UOB Group

m. /hu

United Overseas Bank Singapore

